あの行商のおっちゃん 峠1つ越えたあたりとか言ってやがったのに
That peddler said
it was just behind that mountain pass.
3つも越えたじゃねぇか
More like three mountains.
もう変なこと覚えちまったなぁ…
Bro's picked up
a weird habit too.
どろろ 馬だ
Dororo, a horse.
こんなことならおいらたちもどっかで 馬手に入れるんだった…
Yeah, we should've gotten one
if it was going to be this far.
もしこの村に刀鍛冶がいなくたって おいらもう歩かねぇからな
I'm not walking any further
even if that blacksmith isn't here.
ダメだ これが欲しい
No, I need this.
ここにないなら また歩く
If not here, we walk more.
わかってるわかってる 今のは本当に思ったことじゃねぇから
I know, I didn't really mean that.
そうか
Okay.
確か宗綱って言ってたな その刀鍛冶
I think he said the swordmaker's name
was Munetsuna.
よし 行こうぜ、あにき
All right, let's go bro.
この世界を裏切って
Betrayed this world
腹のなかで蠢いている
And it simmers within
ハラワタ食い破って
Rupturing my innards
赤黒く漲っている
Swelling a reddish black
焼けた皮膚を破るまで
Until the sun burnt skin ruptures
滾る闇の奥に光が在って
There is a light
in the depths of the seething darkness
遠く声を確かめ合って
Confirming each other's voices
in the distance
濡れた指先で撫でるように
As if to stroke with wet fingertips
いつか君に触って
I'd like to touch you one day
闇の奥に光が在って
There is a light
in the depths of the darkness
遠く声を確かめ合って
Confirming each other's voices
in the distance
濡れた指先で撫でるように
As if to stroke with wet fingertips
いつか君に触ってみせるよ
I'd like to touch you one day
#19 The story of the Amanojaku
宗綱？それなら村はずれに住んでる
Munetsuna? He lives on the outskirts
of the village.
ホントか？
-Really?
-Yeah.
だけどあんた まさか刀でも打たせようってんじゃねぇだろうな
But you're not going to ask him
to forge a sword, are you?
え？だってとんでもない名工なんだろ？
But he's a really skilled craftsman,
right?
あの人にそんな大層な腕はねぇよ
Nah, he's nothing of the sort.
ちょっと待てよ 話と違うじゃねぇかい
Hey, that's not what the peddler told us.
そこのナタも打ってもらったが全然大したことねぇ
He forged that hatchet for me,
but I'm not impressed at all.
何より あそこのおこわって娘が また性格も器量も悪いし
And his daughter, Okowa, is really ugly
and has a bad personality.
前々からどうも気に入らなくてよぉ…
I've never liked them too much.
はぁーい！
Yes.
はいはい どうせまたお父の文句言いに来たんでしょ…
Coming. Here to complain
about my papa again?
あ…あれ、どちらさん？
Who are you?
ここ…
Hi.
宗綱って人の家かい？
Is this Munetsuna's place?
宗綱は私のお父だけど…
Yeah, that's my papa.
じゃあ、あんたがおこわ？
Then you're Okowa?
そうやよ？
Yeah, so what?
実は…旅の途中であんたのお父ちゃんが 名のある刀鍛冶だって聞いてきたんだけど
We were traveling and heard that
your papa forged great swords.
あぁ、お客さん！お父はこの国一番の刀工やよ
Oh, a customer. Yeah, my papa's
the best swordmaker in the land.
あぁ…ただ、その…
But you see...
村のやつがさ…
The villagers...
ったく ここの連中はホント素直じゃねぇんだ
Jeez. The people here
always lie like that.
そのくせいっつもお父のとこ来んだから
But they still come to Papa for help.
じゃあ、ホントに腕はいいんだな？
So he's really good?
当たり前だがね！
Of course he is.
そんならあにきのこの刀 打ち直せるか？
Then can he reforge these for us?
だいぶ使い込んだ刀やね…
Wow, they've really been through a lot.
あ あにき！
Hey, bro!
おこわ…
Okowa.
なにすんだあんた！
What are you doing!
あにき！それはやんなって！
Bro, I told you not to do that!
なぜだ
Why?
とにかくやっちゃダメなんだってば！
You just can't.
なぜだ
-Why?
-Because I say so!
なぜもヘチマもねーの！
ヘチマって…なんだ？
I don't get it.
打ってるときにヘタに話しかけると怒られる
He might get mad if we disturb him.
ちょっと待っとるんやよ
Wait right here.
こういう時は初めの印象だがね…
First impressions are really important,
you know.
刀を出しといて！
Have your sword out.
あっ あにき面白ぇモンがあるぞ
Hey, look at that funny thing.
お父 お客さんだ
Papa, you have customers.
刀打ってくれって
He wants you to reforge some swords.
多分 私を嫁にもらう気だがね！
He probably wants to marry me, too.
これ！
-What are you doing!
-Hey.
おい
あぁお父、怒っちゃいかんよ！
Papa, don't get angry.
こういうときは初めの印象が肝心だがね
First impressions are important, okay?
その刀…
Those swords.
お前…何を斬ってきた？
What have you killed with them?
どういうことだがね 刀を供養するなんて初めてだ
Why are we doing this?
We've never purified a sword before.
お前は知らんでいい
You don't need to know.
この御本尊は毘沙門天さま
Bishamon, the guardian god
looks over this temple.
お父や村のみんなが信仰してるんやよ
Papa and everyone else at the village
pray to it.
そのひょっとこはまた別の鍛冶の神様だがね
That Hyottoko is another god.
One of forging.
えっ？これも？こんな顔してんのに
This is a god? It has a funny face.
それは釜の火を吹くときの顔！
That's because it's blowing on the embers.
火ぃ吹くとき？
Blowing on embers?
厄払いとして代々うちに伝わる とってもありがたーいものなんやよ！
It's been passed down for generations
in our family to keep away misfortune.
火を吹く男？ひょっとこ？
The Hyottoko god, blowing on embers huh.
こーんな顔しねぇだろ
Nobody blows on embers like this.
あにき どうした？
What's wrong, bro?
おい
Hey.
刀をその台ヘ置け
Put the swords there.
あ…あぁ
Okay.
あにき…何してんだ！
What the heck are you doing, bro?
何を…？
-What...?
-Jeez.
もぉー
ふざけてる場合じゃないだろぉ
This isn't the time to fool around.
"INN"
疲れたなぁ
I'm pooped.
宗綱のおっちゃん　刀ができたらここに持って来てくれるってさ
That Munetsuna guy said he'd bring
the swords here when they're done.
刀が…ここに来る
The swords will come here...?
あぁ それまでゆっくりしようぜ
Yeah. So let's get some rest till then.
打ち直し代も思ったほどじゃなかったし 骨休みしながら待つとしようぜ
It's not going to cost us as much
as I thought, so we can just relax here.
いらない
Don't need them.
やっぱり疲れが溜まってるみてぇだ 刀いらねぇって聞こえちまったや
I must be really tired. I thought I heard
you say you didn't need them.
い・ら・な・い
Don't need them...
なに言ってんだよ！ 刀がなきゃ鬼神から身体取り戻せねぇだろ⁉
What the heck do you mean?
You need them to get your body back.
百様、どろろちゃん おこわだがね
Mr. Hyaku, Dororo. It's me, Okowa.
どうぞ！
Come in.
…百様？
Mr. Hyaku?
お腹減ってるかと思って 作って持ってきた！
I thought you might be hungry,
so I made this.
ありがてぇ！ちょうど腹減ってたんだ！
Thanks, I was getting hungry.
おわぁうまそう！
Wow, looks yummy.
これ！どろろちゃん こういうものは旦那様が先だがね
No, Dororo. The master of the house
gets to eat first.
は？旦那様って誰だよ！
Master? And who's that?
おいおい あにきはおいらと大事な旅の途中なんだぞ？
Hey, bro and I are on
a really important journey right now.
刀が治ったらここを出てくんだからな？
Once the swords are done, we're leaving.
ついていく覚悟はもうできた！
I'm prepared to go with you.
バカ！ただの旅じゃねぇんだ！ あにきと旅できるのなんておいらくらいなの！
Are you crazy? It's not some joyride.
I'm the only one who can handle it.
心配ない！ 私は国一番の刀工 宗綱の娘だがね！
Don't worry. I'm the daughter of
the land's best swordmaker.
あぁーもう！あにきもはっきり言ってやれよ！
Dang it, you tell her bro.
おこわとは一緒にいられないってさぁ
That you can't be with Okowa.
おこわと一緒にいる
I will be with Okowa.
百様…！
Mr. Hyaku!
冗談でもそういうこと言うなよあにき
Hey, you shouldn't joke around like that.
本気
Not joking.
じゃあ旅は？
-But the journey...
-I quit.
やめる
戻ってねぇ身体は？
And the rest of your body?
いらない このままで…いい
Don't want it. I'm fine like this.
身体？
Body?
いい加減にしねぇとおいらだって怒るぞ⁉
-Stop joking already, I mean it.
-Not joking.
本気
じゃあおいらはどうすんだよ！
Then what about me?
もう一緒じゃなくて…いい
Don't have to be together anymore.
いやいや百様 私は構わねぇ
Mr. Hyaku, I don't mind, really.
どろろちゃんは一緒にいてくれていいやよ
Dororo can stay with us.
もう1回言ってみろよ…
Say that again...
どろろは一緒じゃなくていい
I don't need Dororo with me.
なら勝手にしろぃ！あにきとは絶交だ！
Fine, have it your way. I hate you!
このコンコンチキのバカヤロー！
You big ole dummy idiot jerk!
いいか！ あにきとおこわが一緒になるなんて おいらすっごく嬉しいんだからな！
Listen here. I'm really glad that
you and Okowa are getting together!
…あれ？おいら今なんて…
-What did I just...?
-Oh, Dororo.
どろろちゃん…！
見れば見るほどお似合いだよ！
You two were meant for each other!
あんやとぉ 嬉しい！
Thank you, I'm so happy.
静かだよ！全くもってその通り！
Keep talking. I really think so.
どろろちゃん
-Oh, Dororo.
-Mumble, grumble, rumble...
おけらかんぱぁ…！
百様の馴れ鮨を！
That's Mr. Hyaku's sushi!
どろろちゃん…泣いとったね
Little Dororo, crying for us like that.
どろろが…嬉しそうだ
Dororo looked happy.
あにきのバカ
Bro, you big ole jerk.
もうあにきなんかどうなっちまったって知らねぇんだから
I don't care about you anymore. I mean it.
なんだ？
What's going on?
ご愁傷様 こんたんびはほんに役帳もないことで
My condolences. What a great tragedy.
ほんにいとけしだこって お先真っ暗やなぁ
Yes, it truly is.
Only bad things to come now.
あんやとぉ あんやとぉさん
Thank you. Thank you so much.
百様と祝言挙げるってって村のみんなに言ったら こんなことになってしまったがね
I told the villagers that I was going
to marry you, and now look at all this.
おこわちゃん
Okowa, my dear.
馬子にも衣装って言うけど おこわちゃんが着たら大層みっともにゃあもん作るで
They say wedding attire makes a girl glow.
I'll make one to make you look shabby.
あしめして待っとるだで
You can count on me.
はいはい まったくみんな相変わらずだ…
Okay then.
They're always like this.
よかったなおこわ
Good for you, Okowa.
前々から早くお嫁に行けばいいのにって思ってたんだよ
I'd been hoping you'd hurry up
and get married.
いい祝言になるといいな
Hope you have a good wedding.
あんやとぉ…
Wow, thanks.
なんか 急に素直になったがね…
He's honest for once.
祝言とは…なんだ？
What's a wedding?
百様と私が夫婦になることでしょうが
It means you and I
are going to be husband and wife.
めおと…
Husband and wife...
早いほうがいいと思って 日取りは明日にしといたがね
I thought the earlier the better,
so I set it for tomorrow.
そりゃいくらなんでも
That's way too fast.
わかった
Okay.
待ちやがれこんにゃろーっ！
Wait a second, you idiot!
なにが祝言だ！そんなのおいらが一番に お祝いしなきゃダメじゃねーか！
Wedding? Hah! I congratulate you
from the bottom of my heart!
いいか 誰が なんと言おうと
Listen here.
No matter what anyone might say,
あにきは おこわと 幸せんなるんだぞ！
you're gonna be happy together.
幸せになるね どろろちゃん
We sure will be, Dororo.
ちくしょう…おいらどうしちまったってんだ！
Gosh dang it, what's happened to me?
これ！また食べて…！
Hey, don't eat that!
どろろ 大丈夫だ
Dororo, it's okay.
おこわと…めおとになる
I will become Okowa's husband.
どろろ…嬉しそうだ
Dororo looked happy.
なんだい！あにきのやつ！
What the heck, bro?
すっかりおこわに熱上げちまいやがって！
All head over heels for Okowa.
そんなにあれが好みかよ！
You like her so much, huh?
上等だい！そんならおいらだって考えがあるんだからな！
Fine then. You have it your way,
and I'll have it mine.
どろろ…
Dororo...
みっともないみっともない！
My, how ugly you look.
なんだろうねぇこの子は！ せっかくの衣装が台無しだよ
Such a plain girl.
You put this lovely kimono to waste.
百様！向こう向いてなきゃダメだがね！
Mr. Hyaku, you're not supposed to see yet.
なーんてみっともないんだ！
My, my. How ugly.
刀が…ここに来る
The swords will come here.
刀がいらねぇならおいらが捨ててやらぁ
If he doesn't need the swords,
I'll throw them away.
ホントに捨てちまうんだからな…
I really am going to do it.
何してやがんだ
What are you doing here?
びっくりさせんな！
-Don't scare me like that.
-Who's scaring who?
お前が言うな
これ…あにきの新しい？
This is bro's new sword?
途中だがな 念のため祓いをしてきた
It's not done yet.
I've just been to purify it.
で そいつをどうするつもりだ
What were you going to do with that one?
それで刀を捨てようとしたのか
So that's why you wanted
to throw them away.
あにきは急にやる気なくしちまうし
Bro suddenly lost interest in the journey.
おいらは心にもねぇこと言っちまうし
And I say things I don't mean.
どうすりゃいいんだかわからなくて
I don't know what to do now.
あにきったら おいらの気持ちなんかちっともわかってねぇ
Bro doesn't understand how I feel at all.
おいら あにきに出会ってからたくさん助けてもらったんだ
He's helped me out a whole bunch
ever since we met.
だから これからあにきが辛いときは絶対おいらが助けてやるんだって
So I'd made up my mind to help him
get through rough times.
決めたのに…
I swore that I would.
なのに…
But now...
なんで旅やめるなんて言うんだよ
How can he quit the journey now?
迎えに来た
I came for you.
この前迎えに来てくれたばっかりじゃねぇかい バカ野郎…
You just came for me a few days ago.
You jerk.
おいら…いつのまにか寝ちまったのかい
Did I just fall asleep?
気が散る
-Don't bother me.
-Sorry.
あぁ…ごめんよ
おっちゃん…おこわの祝言には行かないのかい？
Aren't you going to Okowa's wedding?
刀工にとって 刀より優先するものはない
Nothing is more important to a swordmaker
than making swords.
おこわも承知している
Okowa understands.
よっぽど刀が好きなんだな
You really like swords, huh.
お前は嫌いか
You hate them?
おいら 侍嫌いなんだ
I hate samurai.
だから人を殺す刀も好きじゃない
So I don't like swords made for killing.
俺も人殺しは嫌いだ
I hate people killing people, too.
俺の理想は争いを止める刀を作ることだ
My ideal is to make a sword
that makes fighting cease.
それを見た相手が一瞬でかなわねぇと感じる刀をな
A sword that makes the enemy see
that they're no match and give up.
そんなモン作れんのかい
Is that even possible?
そうたやすくはあるまい
It won't be easy,
生きてるうちに作れるかもわからん
I might not live to see it happen.
わかるのは 力の使い道を間違えちゃいけねぇってことだけだ
I just know I shouldn't use my powers
for the wrong cause.
おいら…やっぱりあにきのそばについててやんなきゃ
I was wrong. I have to stay by bro's side.
それも 心にもない言葉なのか？
Do you really mean that?
そんなんじゃねぇや！
Of course I do!
あれ？そういやおいら ずっと思った事喋ってるじゃねぇか
Huh? I've been saying
what I really mean, haven't I?
なんでここだと普通に喋れんだ？
Why am I okay when I'm here?
っていうか いつからあべこべになっちまったんだっけ…
Wait, since when have I
been talking in opposites?
あにきは…あにきは
Bro... What about him?
いつからおかしかったっけ！
Since when has he been weird?
あの寺だ！
That temple!
さぁ！２人でお寺に行くんだがね！
-Come on, we have to go to the temple.
-Why?
なぜだ
To get married, come on.
この村は仏前式だからやよ！
そのあと村のみんながお祝いしてくれる…！
The villagers will hold a celebration
for us afterwards.
刀がここに来る
The swords will come here.
お寺から戻ったら刀も来るから！
They can come
when we get back from the temple.
刀がここに来る
The swords will come here.
もしかしてお前の仕業か⁉
Was it you that did all this?
やっぱり！
I knew it.
どろろちゃん
-Dororo?
-Bro!
あにき！
何あのバケモンは⁉
What's that creature!
たぶんおいらたちがおかしくなっちまったのはあいつのせいだ！
That ghoul is probably what made us
act weird.
とっ捕まえよう！
Get it!
違う違う！あっちあっち！
No, that way!
違うって！あにき あっち！
No, not me. Over there!
百様！何してるんだがね！
Mr. Hyaku, what are you doing?
どろろ…
Dororo...
あに…き…
Bro...
どろろちゃんが…死んでまう！百様！
You're going to kill Dororo, stop!
どろろちゃん！大丈夫？
Dororo, are you okay?
どろろ…
Dororo.
あにき…
Bro.
ごめんよ 疑っちまって
I'm sorry I doubted you.
まさか本当にいたとはな…
Who'd have thought it was real.
ぜーんぶこのバケモンのせいだったんやねぇ
So it was all this ghoul's fault.
この寺にゃぁ むかし村で散々悪さをした あまのじゃくが封じられてるという
Legend has it there was once an Amanojaku
that worked mischief in the village.
It was confined here.
言い伝えがあった
私ら ホントに厄払いの力で守られてたんやね
So we really were protected
by the Hyottoko gods.
けど こいついつから出てきちまってたんだ？
But when did it get out?
さぁな
Who knows?
さーて 百様とどろろちゃんも仲直りできたし
Now then, Mr. Hyaku and Dororo
are back to being friends again.
これで心置きなく祝言が…ん？
So let's get on with the wedding...
バケモンのせいでみんなあべこべなことを言ってた…
Wait, if everyone was speaking
in opposites because of the ghoul...
ってことは
That means...
どろろちゃんも百様も？
Dororo and Mr. Hyaku were too, and...
というわけだがね 百様は悪くないんやよ
So you see, it's not Mr. Hyaku's fault.
すいませんでした
I'm sorry.
おこわ！そんなやつと一緒んなる必要はねぇ！
Okowa, you don't need to marry him anyway.
今まで…ずっと思ってたことを素直に言えなかった
I couldn't tell you
how I felt all this time.
この仏頂面なんかより 絶対お前を幸せにしてやる！
But I promise to make you happier
than grouchy face here.
俺と…一緒んなってくれないか！
Will you marry me?
なんだこれ
Whatever.
おこわが嬉しそうだ
Okowa looks happy.
すっげぇ
Wow.
言ったがね！お父は国一番の刀工やよって
I told you,
Papa's the best swordmaker in the land.
刀が…来た
The swords are here.
どうだい？気に入った？
You like them?
あにき 嬉しそうだな
Bro looks so happy.
俺が…嬉しそうだ
I look happy.
こいつらは 常人には想像もつかない過酷な運命を辿ってきたんだ
They've been through harsh fates
no normal human could even imagine.
きっとこれから先もな
And it's not over for them yet.
どのみちお前が入り込む余地はなかった
There was no place for you by his side
to begin with.
そりゃああんなバケモンばっかり相手してるんじゃ 無理だがね
No doubt about that. Dealing with
ghouls like that all the time.
百様！もうあんまり人におでこくっつけちゃぁダメやよ？
-Don't rub your head on people anymore.
-Why?
なぜだ
なぜもヘチマもねぇの！
Because it'll go pear-shaped!
ヘチマってなんだ
Pear...?
あとで教えてやるよ
I'll explain later.
それじゃ そろそろ行くかい あにき
Let's get going then, bro.
どろろも一緒だ
You go with me.
当たり前だろ？あにきと旅ができるのはおいらだけなんだから
Duh. I'm the only one
who can handle this journey with you.
2人が…嬉しそうだ
We look happy.
救いなどない
Born into this world
生まれ落ちてきた
There is no salvation
歪な心の形に
The distorted shape of the heart
勇ましい鼓動の叫び
Yet it beats courageously
振り向きやしない
There is no turning back
修羅の道だって
Even from the path of evil
枯れ行く季節など越えて
Witnessing the withering seasons
確かな答えを探した
We search for the truth
醜い姿に
In our ugliness
その痛みさえも気づけないまま 僕たちは
We don't even recognize the pain
この皮も剥がしてしまったの
As we peel back the skin
ああ　いつだって　愚かさに苛まれているの
We are forever tormented by our stupidity
でもさあ　辛くなって
But if the dawn never comes
終わらない夜ならば
Through the painful night
きっと 疑わぬあなた
You who distrusts nothing
呪われた世界を愛せるから
You will be able to love
this accursed world
すべてを背負って　今
Now that we carry the world
on our shoulders
取り戻すの
It's time to take it back
"Amanojaku"